<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graham Pople&#39;s site</title>
    <link>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Graham Pople&#39;s site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 09:50:29 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Enter the Matrix</title>
      <link>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/enter-the-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 09:50:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/enter-the-matrix/</guid>
      <description>A simple immutable library for vector and matrix maths, written in Scala. There&amp;rsquo;s a surprising lack of these, with the existing Scala matrix libraries being heavyweight, rather complex, and generally part of a much large statistical package. I wanted something lightweight for 3D maths.
It&amp;rsquo;s designed to be very safe, concise, and easy to use:
 val m1 = Matrix4x4.identity val m2 = Matrix4x4.scale(1.0f) val m3 = Matrix4x4.rotateAroundXAxis(30.0f) val m4: Matrix4x4 = m3 * m2 * m1 val v1 = Vector4(0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiniPlay</title>
      <link>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/miniplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 09:50:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/miniplay/</guid>
      <description>This desktop widget lets you control the web-based Google Play Music.
The widget is coded in Scala and uses ScalaFX for the UI. There&amp;rsquo;s also a Chrome extension, written in Javascript, which interacts with Google Play Music. IPC between the two is with Websockets.
The Chrome extension source and desktop widget source are on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split the Bill</title>
      <link>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/split-the-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 09:50:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/split-the-bill/</guid>
      <description>An Android app, written in Scala and published on the Google Play Store.
This app&amp;rsquo;s not going to win any design or complexity awards, but was more of a successful hobby project to learn Android development and publish an app in a few days.
The source is on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Parser</title>
      <link>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/100-c-transpiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:50:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/100-c-transpiler/</guid>
      <description>CParser on github is my library that turns valid C code into a clean abstract syntax tree (AST), and can be embedded in any JVM-language project.
This could be useful for e.g. a JVM-based C compiler, transpiler, prettifier, or IDE plugin.
The code is written in Scala and transpiled to Javascript with ScalaJS so it can be embedded directly here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Personal Site</title>
      <link>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/1000-personal-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:50:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/1000-personal-site/</guid>
      <description>This site is coded with the static site generator Hugo.
Having used Wordpress for blogging duties in the past, I&amp;rsquo;m a big convert to static site generators. They&amp;rsquo;re much faster, both for adding and consuming content.
The source is on Github and it&amp;rsquo;s hosted on Git Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undiscovered Guide</title>
      <link>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/300-undiscovered-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:50:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gropple.github.io/Words/projects/300-undiscovered-guide/</guid>
      <description>Undiscovered Guide is a travel website I created with my partner while we were travelling, to help others explore our favourite parts of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty popular, getting over 30,000 monthly page views.
There&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on under the hood:
 Parts of it are a dynamically-created single page app. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Scala, transpiled to Javascript with ScalaJS. The backend CMS is custom and written from scratch in Scala.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>